《暮光之城2：新月》
这种狂暴的快乐往往预示着狂暴的结局
These violent delights have violent ends,
那欢愉的霎那  正如火与火药
and in their triumph die, like fire and powder,
一吻即逝
which, as they kiss, consume.
奶奶
Gran？
别出来  爱德华  她会看见你的
Edward, don't！She'll see you.
好吧
Okay.
奶奶  这位是
Gran, I'd like you to meet…
贝拉  生日快乐
Happy birthday, Bella.
生日快乐  贝尔
Happy birthday, Bells..
我说过的  不用准备礼物
I thought we agreed, no presents.
我的没包装  所以不算
Well, the one from me's not wrapped, so it doesn't count.
真是太棒了  谢谢你  爸爸
That's actually great. Thanks, Dad.
然后这个是你妈送的  我们商量了一下
It goes with this one from your mom. We coordinated.
其实是她说服了我
Well, she coordinated me.
可以用来放你高三这年的照片
It's to put your pictures in from senior year.
已经高三啦
Senior year.
- 你怎么老得这么快  - 我没有啊  我还没那么老
- How'd you get so old so fast？ - l didn't. It's not that old.
我可不知道  那是根白头发吗
I don't know. Is that a gray hair？
不是  不可能
No. No way.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
这可真有趣
That's really funny.
加上这名失踪的登山者已有3起疑似死亡
Another missing hiker brings the total to three presumed dead.
护林员正在寻找这只杀人野兽
Rangers are searching for the killer animal…
情况很棘手
Situation's a！！critica！
走之前先探好路
You've got to look first before you go
是贝拉  贝拉
It's Bella. Bella！
- 嗨  - 我…
- Hi.  - I'm…
今天可是个大日子
Today's the big day, Bella.
罗米欧与朱丽叶的论文写了吗
R and J essay due.
- 嗯  写了  - 为何你如此美丽  贝拉
- Oh, yeah. - Wherefore art thou, Bella？
我想给你们照张照片  我妈妈想要我收集些照片
Let me take a picture of you guys. My mom wants me to put together, like,
做一个满是回忆的剪贴簿
a scrapbook full of memories.
- 哦  - 真棒
- Oh. - Cool. Yeah.
我来拍  我不照
I take them. I'm not in them.
- 不行  过来  - 今天得照
- No, no, no, come here. - Well, you are today.
要是我鼻子显得太大了记得修一下
You'll photoshop this if my nose looks big, right？
别担心  边上有我呢  没人会注意看你们的
Don't worry, I’m in the picture. No one will be looking at you guys.
很好
That's good.
太好了  科林家族来了
Oh, good. Cullen's here.
等会见
Well, talk to you later.
- 生日快乐  - 不用你提醒我
- Happy birthday. - Don't remind me.
贝拉  你的出生是很值得庆祝的
Bella, your birth is definitely something to celebrate.
- 可我的年龄不用  - 你的年龄
- Yeah, but my aging's not. - Your aging？
18岁就担心这个太早了点
I think 18 is a little young to start worrying about that.
已经比你大一岁了
Its one year older than you.
才没有  我109岁了
No, it isn't. I’m 109.
或许我不该和这么老的人约会
Well, maybe I shouldn't be dating such an old man.
太恶心了  我应该感到厌烦
It’s gross. I should be thoroughly repulsed.
- 该去上课了  - 好
- We have to go to class. - Okay.
等一下
Wait a second.
有人找你
Someone wants you.
- 贝拉  - 雅各布
- Bella！- Jacob！
什么
What？
你们慢慢谈
I'll leave you to talk.
你好啊  肌肉男  合成代谢类固醇对你身体不好
Hello, biceps！You know, anabolic steroids are really bad for you.
我只是长壮了  贝拉
Well, I’m just filling out, Bella.
如果经常见面就不会这么明显
You know, it wouldn't seem so drastic if we hung out more.
你应该换换学校  这样你就能多和白人接触了
You should switch schools. You can come hang out with the palefaces.
没关系的  我更喜欢印第安学校的排外主义
I’m all right. I prefer the rez school's exclusivity.
这里任凭种族恩怨充斥
They let any old riffraff into this place.
那您大驾光临有何贵干呀
I see. Then why are you slumming it？
我来这给跑车买零件
l was just buying a part for the Rabbit.
等我装好了  你真该兜一圈儿
You should really come take a ride when it's done.
很快吗
Is it fast？
还不错吧
It’s decent.
- 说着玩儿的  - 好吧
- I’m kidding. - Okay. Good.
对了  生日快乐
Hey, happy birthday.
你爸告诉我爸了
Your dad told my dad, so…
我一猜就是
Yeah, of course he did.
前几天我一看到这个就想到了要送给你
I saw this the other day and thought of you.
它能带走噩梦
Catches bad dreams.
太棒了
That's kind of perfect.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
No problem.
- 真高兴看见你  - 回头见
- Good seeing you. - Yeah, I’ll see you later.
拜
Bye.
凭什么雅各布·布莱克能送礼物而我不能
So how come Jacob Black gets to give you a gift and I don't？
因为我没有什么可以回赠你的
Because I have nothing to give back to you.
贝拉  你的一呼一吸就是我的全部
Bella, you give me everything just by breathing.
是吗  谢谢
See？Thank you.
- 这就足够了  - 贝拉
- That's all l want. - Bella！
生日快乐
Happy birthday！
我说了不用送礼物的
I thought I said no presents.
我预见了你打开后的样子  猜猜怎样
I've already seen you open it, and guess what,
你会爱死这个的
you love it.
今晚你穿上这个  到我家来吧
You're gonna wear it tonight. Our place.
来嘛来嘛  会很有趣的
Come on. Please？It'll be fun.
- 好吧  我去  - 太好了
- Okay. All right. - Great！
7点见
Okay, I’ll see you at 7:00.
贾斯帕  这不公平  你控制我的情绪
Jasper, no fair with the mood control thing.
对不起  贝拉  生日快…
Sorry, Bella. Happy…
还是算了吧
Never mind.
吸血鬼是不能相信的  相信我
You can't trust vampires. Trust me.
我的爱人  我的妻子
O my love！My wife！
死亡虽然带走了你甜美的呼吸
Death, that hath sucked the honey of thy breath
却无法夺走你的美丽
hath had no power yet upon thy beauty.
你未被征服
Thou art not conquered.
你的嘴唇和脸颊仍然红润美艳
Beauty's ensign yet is crimson in thy lips and in thy cheeks.
不曾让苍白进占
And death's pale flag is not advanced there.
我讨厌庆祝生日
I hate being celebrated.
有很多事比这更糟  你看罗密欧
There are worse tragedies. l mean, look at Romeo.
他的愚蠢杀死了自己的真爱
Killed his true love out of sheer stupidity.
没错
Yeah.
但我还是嫉妒他  只因为一件事
Though l do envy him one thing.
是啊  朱丽叶简直完美无瑕
Juliet is, like, perfect.
如果你喜欢外表美丽的东西
lf you like that obviously beautiful sort of thing.
不是因为那个姑娘  是因为自杀
Not the girl, the suicide.
对于我们种族来说
It’s nearly impossible for…
这几乎是不可能的
For some people.
对于人类  一点毒药
For humans, a little poison,
一把刺进心脏的匕首
a dagger to the heart.
可选的方法太多了
There's so many different options.
你为什么这么说
Why would you say that？
因为我曾经想过自杀
Because I had to consider it once.
如果没能及时救出你我该怎么办
I didn't know if I’d get to you in time.
我必须要想一些后备计划
I had to come up with some kind of plan.
什么样的后备计划
What was the plan？
我会去意大利  激怒沃尔图里家族
That I’d go to Italy and provoke the Volturi.
- 什么  - 沃尔图里家族
- The what？ - The Volturi.
现在  谁能复述一下最后几句台词
Now, who'd like to repeat the last few lines of iambic pentameter
以表明他听课了
just to show they were paying attention？
科林先生
Mr. Cullen？
好的  博迪先生
Yes, Mr. Berty.
"在这里  我要安心长眠
"O here will I set up my everlasting rest
使这厌倦世俗的肉体挣脱宿命的枷锁
"and shake the yoke of inauspicious stars from this world-wearied flesh.
双眼最后望向你
"Eyes, look your last.
双臂最后拥抱你
"Arms, take your last embrace！
在你的双唇  呼吸的所在
"And, lips, O you, the doors of breath,
印下堂堂正正的一吻  与死神签下永世的契约"
seal with a righteous kiss a dateless bargain to engrossing death！"
看屏幕  同学们
Eyes on the screen, people.
就这样  一个亲吻  我走向死亡
Thus with a kiss I die.
沃尔图里家族非常古老  力量非常强大
The Volturi are a very old, very powerful family.
是我们世界类似王室的家族
l guess they're the closest thing to royalty my world has.
- 那是卡莱尔吗  - 没错
- Is that Carlisle？- Yeah.
他和他们一起住了几十年
He lived with them for a few decades.
说他们很文雅  当然  并不看重人类的性命
Described them as very refined. No respect for human life, of course,
但起码尊重艺术和科技
but a respect for the arts and the sciences, at least.
还有法律
And the law.
法律高于一切
Above all, the law.
吸血族也有法律吗
Vampires have laws？
并不多
Not very many.
只有一条是必须遵守的
And only one that's regularly enforced.
是什么
What is it？
确保我们的存在不为外人所知
That we keep the existence of our kind a secret.
我们不会让自己引人注意
We don't make spectacles of ourselves,
也不会光天化日下杀戮
and we don't kill conspicuously.
当然  除非是你自己想死
Unless, of course, you want to die.
别再说这个了
You gotta stop talking about that.
我简直不敢去想有人伤害你
I can't even think about someone hurting you.
贝拉  唯一能让我受伤的只有你
Bella, the only thing that can hurt me is you.
其他的我无所畏惧
And I don't have anything else to be afraid of.
可事实不是这样的
That's not true.
维多利亚吗  总有一天她会来找我
Victoria？She'll come for me one day.
爱丽丝能够看到她的决定  我们可以做好准备
Alice will see when she decides, and we'll be ready.
我可以保护你
I could protect you
如果你把我变成吸血鬼的话
if you change me.
贝拉  你已经在保护我了
Bella, you already do protect me.
你是我继续活下去的
You're my only reason
唯一理由
to stay alive,
如果我算是活着的话
if that's what I am.
保护你不受任何人伤害是我的责任
But it's my job to protect you.
除了我妹妹
From everyone except my sister.
开始了  时间到了  要开始了
It’s time！It’s time. It’s time. It’s time！
你唇如荨麻
Your lips are nettles
你舌似美酒
Your tongue is wine
你像液体般流走  但你身躯如松
You're left as liquid. But your body's pine
真抱歉
Sorry about all this.
- 我们试图管住爱丽丝  - 似乎永远不可能
- We tried to rein Alice in. - As if that were even possible.
- 生日快乐  贝拉  - 谢谢
- Happy birthday, Bella. - Thanks.
我在你包里找到的  不介意吧
I found it in your bag. You mind？
姐弟恋  真新潮
Dating an older woman. Hot.
- 怎么了  - 你先来  罗莎莉
- What？- You first, Rosalie.
是一条项链  爱丽丝挑的
It’s a necklace. Alice picked it out.
谢谢
Thanks.
来秀个恩爱
Show me the love.
这是艾美特送的
This one's from Emmett.
已经装到你的卡车上了
Already installed it in your truck.
那辆破车终于能有个
Finally a decent sound system
- 像样的音响了  - 别这么说  又不是车的错
- for that piece of… - Hey！Don't hate the truck.
看看埃斯米和卡莱尔的
Open Esme and Carlisle's.
是能让你每天都愉快的小玩意
Just a little something to brighten your day.
我们觉得你最近的脸色不太好
Yes, you've been looking kind of pale lately.
被纸划伤了
Paper cut.
贾斯  贾斯  放松点  只是一点
Jaz, Jaz. It’s okay. It’s just a little
血
blood.
把贾斯帕带出去
Get Jasper out of here.
我很抱歉  我  我不能再待了
I’m sorry, I can't.
去我的工作室我给你缝合
I’ll have to stitch this up in my office.
去看看贾斯帕
Check on Jasper.
他肯定对自己非常失望
I’m sure he's very upset with himself,
恐怕现在除你以外没人能劝动他
and I doubt he'll listen to anyone but you right now.
爱德华
Edward.
- 我根本就不该来  - 不是你的错
- l never wanted to have a party. - It’s not your fault.
贾斯帕还没习惯远离人类的鲜血
Jasper hasn't been away from human blood as long as the rest of us.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it？
年复一年的磨练
Years and years of practice.
难道你就没想过让它顺其自然吗
Did you ever think of just doing it the easy way？
没有
No.
我知道自己想成为什么样的人  我想要帮助别人
I knew who I wanted to be. I wanted to help people.
这能给我带来快乐  尽管我受到诅咒
It brings me happiness, even if l am damned regardless.
诅咒？
Damned？
地狱什么的？
Like hell？
卡莱尔  你没有受诅咒
Carlisle, you couldn't be damned.
你没有  不可能
You couldn't. It’s impossible.
谢谢你  贝拉
Thank you, Bella.
你对我们一直都关怀备至
You've always been very gracious about us.
就因为这个吗  就因为这个他才不想把我变成吸血鬼吗
So that's it？That's why he won't change me？
你换过来想想看
Imagine the situation in reverse. Hmm.
如果你像爱德华那样对此深信不疑
If you believed as Edward does,
你愿意夺走他的灵魂吗
could you take away his soul？
你无法永远保护我
You can't protect me
无法面面俱到
from everything.
总有一天  我们会被分开
At some point, something's gonna separate us.
可能由于一个意外  或是疾病
It’s gonna be an accident or illness
或者是因为衰老
or old age,
只要我还是人类就会这样  唯一的办法就是改变我
as long as I’m human. And the only solution is to change me.
那不是个办法  而是场悲剧
That's not a solution. That's a tragedy.
等我变成老太婆时你就不会爱我了
You're not gonna want me when I look like a grandmother.
贝拉  我对你的感觉你难道一点都不明白吗
Bella, do you not understand my feelings for you at all？
卡莱尔告诉我了
Carlisle told me
你对自己灵魂的质疑
how you feel about your soul.
可我不是那么想的
I don't believe that.
不要顾虑我的灵魂
So don't worry about mine.
你该回屋去了
You should go inside.
我的生日还没过
It’s still my birthday.
我能提个要求吗
So can I ask one thing？
吻我好吗
Kiss me？
我爱你
I love you.
登上你的塔楼
Up with your turret
难道我们只是惶恐罢了
Aren't we just terrified？
页岩  将你的担忧掩盖
Shale, screen your worry
让你无从寻觅
From what you won't ever find
别让它愚弄了你
Don't let it fool you
堕落了你
Down
陪我走走吧
Just come take a walk with me.
我们要离开福克斯了
We have to leave Forks.
为什么
Why？
卡莱尔的外表本该比现在的老十岁的
Carlisle's supposed to be 10 years older than he looks,
人们慢慢注意到这点了
and people are starting to notice.
好吧  我会想办法向查理解释的
Okay, I’ve gotta think of something to say to Charlie.
你说的"我们"是指…
When you say "we"…
我指的是我家人和我自己
I mean my family and myself.
爱德华  贾斯帕的事  小事而已
Edward, what happened with Jasper, it's nothing.
没错  是小事
You're right. It was nothing,
是我一直担心的事
nothing but what l always expected
而且本该发生比这可怕百倍的事
and nothing compared to what could have happened.
贝拉  你只是不属于我的世界
You just don't belong in my world, Bella.
我属于你
I belong with you.
不  你不是
No. You don't.
我要跟你一起走
I’m coming.
贝拉
Bella,
我不希望你跟着我走
I don't want you to come.
你不要我了吗
You don't want me？
不要
No.
这会改变很多事情
That changes things a lot.
如果你觉得不过分的话
But if it's not too much to ask,
能答应我件事吗
can you just promise me something？
不要鲁莽行事
Don't do anything reckless.
算是为了查理吧
For Charlie's sake.
而作为回报  我也承诺一件事
And I’ll promise something to you in return.
我保证  这是你最后一次见到我
This is the last time you'll ever see me.
我不会再回来
I won't come back,
我不会再烦打搅你今后的生活
and you can go on with your life without any interference from me.
就像我从未存在过  我保证
It will be like l never existed, I promise.
如果是因为我的灵魂  拿去好了  没有你还要灵魂干什么
lf this is about my soul, take it. l don't want it without you.
这和你的灵魂无关
It’s not about your soul.
你对我来说  不好
You're just not good for me.
我对你来说不够好
Not good enough for you.
很抱歉  打扰你这么久
I’m just sorry l let this go on for so long.
求你
Please…
别
Don't…
再见
Goodbye.
爱德华
Edward.
Edward！
爱德华
Edward.
我再给科林家打电话问问
I’m gonna try the Cullens' place again.
- 查理  科林一家搬出城了  - 走的真是时候
- The Cullens left town, Charlie. - Good riddance.
他们去哪了
Where'd they go？
查理  我们会找到她的
We'll find her, Charlie.
- 谢谢你  - 查理
- Thanks, Harry. - Charlie！
她没事
She's all right.
我来抱吧  谢谢你  山姆
I got her. Thank you, Sam.
(十月)
∮ 有可能吗 ∮
∮ There's a possibility ∮
(十一月)
∮ 我所拥有的 ∮
∮ All that I had ∮
∮ 也是即将得到的 ∮
∮ Was all I’m gonna get ∮
爱丽丝  你消失了
Alice, you've disappeared,
所有一切都消失了
like everything else.
我还能找谁谈心呢  我很失落
Now who else can I talk to？I’m lost.
(十二月)
你离开的时候
When you left,
他也离开了
and he left,
你把一切都带走了
you took everything with you.
满眼望去  都没有他的身影
But the absence of him is everywhere I look.
就像我的胸膛被挖了一个巨大的洞
It’s like a huge hole has been punched through my chest.
贝拉
Bella.
可我还是很开心
But in a way I’m glad.
痛苦提醒着我他曾经存在过
The pain is my only reminder that he was real,
你们都曾经存在过
that you all were.
好了  就这么定了
All right. That's it.
什么
What？
回杰克森维尔和你妈妈一起住吧
You're going to Jacksonville to live with your mother.
我不会离开福克斯的
I’m not leaving Forks.
贝尔  他不会回来了
Bells, he's not coming back.
我知道
I know.
你的行为很不正常
It’s just not normal, this behavior.
老实说  我被你吓坏了  你妈妈也是
Quite frankly, it's scaring the hell out of me and your mother.
宝贝  我也不想你离开
Baby, I don't want you to leave.
我不想  但是  回杰克森维尔吧  交些新朋友
I don't, but just go. Go to Jacksonville. Make some new friends.
我喜欢我的老朋友
I like my old friends.
- 可你们都没联系了  - 我们还有联系
- Well, you never see them anymore. - I do.
明天我要和杰西卡一起去逛街
I’m gonna go shopping tomorrow with Jessica.
- 你讨厌逛街的  - 我…
- You hate shopping. - I…
我要过个女生之夜
I need a girls' night out.
好吧  女生之夜
All right. Girls' night.
逛街
Shopping.
不错  去买些好东西
I like it. Go buy some stuff.
杰西卡  我是贝拉
Hi, Jessica, it's Bella.
没错  贝拉·斯旺
Yeah, Bella Swan.
我不明白你怎么能看完
I don't know why you want to sit through
僵尸吃人  而且还没有帅哥热吻
all those zombies eating people and no hot guys kissing anybody.
真恶心  怎么这么多僵尸片
It’s gross. Like… And why are there that many zombie movies anyway？
是为了类比麻风病吗
'Cause if it's supposed to, like, draw a parallel about leprosy,
我堂兄就有麻风病  这不好笑
my cousin had leprosy. It’s not funny, you know？
还是为了暗讽消费主义
And, like, is it supposed to be a metaphor for consumerism？
警告人们不要自我感觉良好
Because don't be so pleased with your own, like,
或自认为非常精明
self-referential cleverness, you know？
就像某些女孩喜欢逛街  显然不是所有女孩
Like, some girls like to shop. Not all girls, apparently.
所以你给我打电话我非常惊讶
Although I was surprised you even called at all. You know？
你那么消沉  我非常非常担心你
Like, your depression thing, I get it. I’m totally, totally worried.
都这么久了
But after a while it's like,
- 怎么还无法释怀  - 想兜风吗  妞儿
- you're still bumming… - You want a ride, girls？
你知道吗  我也经历过一些事
…and I’m going through stuff, too. You know？Like Mike deciding
比如麦克说只想和我做朋友
he just wants to be friends.
这是怎么了  看看咱钓着什么了
What's up？Look what we found.
那很痛苦
It’s hard, you know？
当他说  "只做朋友吧"…
Like, and since when does "just friends"…
- 怎么了伙计们  - 看看什么上钩了
- What's up guys？- Look what we found.
要去哪啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, where you going？
继续往前走
Keep walking.
这很危险
This is dangerous.
- 快过来  - 过来呀
- Dude, come on. - Come here for a sec！
我觉得我认识那些人
I think I know those guys.
有啤酒  还有摩托车
We got beer！We got bikes！
他们看起来真棒  咱们能走了吗
Well, they seem great. Can we go？
我得过去看看
I’m just gonna see something.
嘿  小妞
Hey, girlie！
很好  有人要搭车了
All right, all right. We got a taker.
转身回去
Turn around.
- 闭嘴  - 你闭嘴
- Shut up！ - You shut up！
抱歉  我认错人了
I’m sorry, I thought you were somebody else.
没事  亲爱的  你说我是谁我就是谁
No, that's cool. I’ll be whoever you want me to be, honey.
你想怎样
So, what do you say？
你向我保证过不鲁莽行事的
You promised me, nothing reckless.
你也保证过永远不再出现的
You promised it would be as if you never existed.
- 你撒谎  - 宝贝  你说什么
- You lied. - You say something, babe？
无所谓了
You know what？Never mind.
停车  停车  停车
Stop！Stop, stop, stop！
你到底哪根筋不对了
Hey, what the hell's wrong with you？
只是好奇
Just curious.
- 我想我看到了一些东西  - 你…
- l thought that l saw something. - You… Oh.
你真是疯了  要么就是有自杀倾向
You're insane, actually. Or suicidal.
那个家伙可能是精神病
That homeboy could've been a psycho.
我差点就去FBI录口供了  就像那些蹩脚的电视纪录片
I was about to end up in an FBI interview room like some lame TV show.
天哪  太刺激了
God, that was such a rush.
太好了  你玩儿上瘾了是吧
Awesome. So you're an adrenaline junkie now？
真酷  那你可以去蹦极
That's cool. You can go bungee jumping.
没必要坐上街头混混的摩托车
You don't get on the back of some random loser's motorcycle.
疯子
Crazy.
爱丽丝  我看到他了
Alice, I saw him.
或许我疯了  那也无所谓
Maybe I’m crazy now. I guess that's okay.
如果冲动地冒险能让我见到他
If a rush of danger is what it takes to see him,
那么我愿意冒这个险
then that's what I’ll find.
贝拉
Bella！
这些日子你跑哪去了  疯丫头
Where the hell have you been, loca？
我给你带了些东西
I brought you something.
- 好  - 可能有点疯狂
- Okay. - It’s a little crazy.
废铁  不是吧
Scrap metal. You shouldn't have.
在废车场找到的
I saved it from the junkyard.
我觉得可能修理这堆破烂不值得
I think they'll probably cost more to fix than they're worth,
但我后来又想  如果有个懂机械的朋友帮忙的话
but then I thought that if l had a mechanic friend
- 我就是那个机械系的朋友吗  - 没错
- Me being the mechanic-type friend？- That's right.
- 你什么时候开始喜欢摩托车了  - 现在开始
- Since when are you into motorcycles？- Since now.
我知道你觉得我这么做很傻很鲁莽
I get it if you think that this is really stupid and reckless.
没错  是非常的傻非常鲁莽
Yeah, I mean, it's completely stupid and reckless.
咱们什么时候开始
When do we start？
现在
Now.
- 拜托  - 好吧
- Please？- All right.
小心点  这东西真的  很重  所以
Oh, hey, be careful. Those things are actually really heavy, so…
雅各布  你真像个大力士
Jake, you're, like, buff.
怎么会这样  你才16岁  我不太明白
How did that happen？You're, like, 16. I don't get it.
年龄只是个数字  宝贝  你现在有40岁了吗
Mmm-hmm. Age is just a number, baby. What are you, like, 40 now？
有时我确实这么认为
It feels like that sometimes.
那首歌不错  你不喜欢吗
That song's good. You don't like it？
我其实不再喜欢听音乐了
I don't really like music anymore, kind of.
好  不听音乐了
Okay. No more music.
我在想  如果我们想每天都能这样
So I was thinking, if we're gonna do this every day,
而且以后也可以的话
and hopefully we will,
咱们就得抽点时间把作业做完
we have to, like, fit some homework in there somewhere.
我不希望比利认为我对你有不好的影响
I don't want Billy thinking that I’m a bad influence on you.
你？ 影响我？ 别逗了
You？Influence me？Please.
你…我比你大啊
Are you… I’m older than you,
所以肯定是我影响你
so that makes me the influencer and you the influence.
不对  不对
No, no, no.
我的块头和头脑都比你成熟
My size and knowledge baseactually makes me older than you
而你柔弱无力且缺乏基本知识
because of your general paleness and lack of know-how.
我说服你帮我组装这个两轮杀人机器
I convinced you to build two-wheeled death machines with me.
你不觉得这让你很滑稽很幼稚吗
Don't you think that makes you kind of young and naive？
好吧  那你觉得应该怎样
Okay. So where do we stand？
- 如果我35岁的话  你最多是32岁  - 不是吧
- I’m 35. And you might be, like, 32. - Come on.
- 雅各  在家吗  - 没关系  哥们儿
- Yo, Jake, you in there？- It’s okay. It’s just my boys.
- 嘿  雅各  - 伙计们  这是贝拉
- Hey, Jake. - Hey. Guys, this is Bella.
贝拉  奎尔和恩布里
Bella, that's Quil and Embry.
我叫奎尔·安特拉
I’m Quil Ateara.
那么修摩托车的事是真的咯
So the bike building story is true.
没错  这些都是我教他的
Oh, yeah, yeah, I taught him everything he knows.
关于你是他女朋友那部分呢
What about the part where you're his girlfriend？
我们只是朋友
We're friends, you know.
露馅了
Burn.
我记得我说过她只是我的女性朋友
Actually, remember I said she's a girl and a friend.
恩布里  当时他说得有这么清楚吗
Embry, do you remember him making that distinction？
没有
Nope.
就是说你们都有女朋友  很不错嘛
So you guys have girlfriends？That's awesome.
是啊  不错  奎尔带去舞会的那个其实是他表妹
Yeah, right. Quil's actually taking his cousin to prom.
没错  依旧很好笑是吧
Yeah, that's still a riot.
你想找乐子吗  我就给你点乐子
You want funny, Black？I’ll give you funny.
天啊
Jeez.
你违规
Hey, that hold's illegal！
我押5美元赌奎尔赢
I got five bucks on Quil.
那你赢定了
You're on.
所有的宇航员  香槟在塑料杯里泛光
All of the astronauts. Champagne in plastic cups
等待着大人物登场
Waiting for the big hero to show
他就站在门外  手托腮
Outside the door he stands. His head in his hands
心快蹦出喉咙
And his heart in his throat
他要告诉他们
What can he tell them now
亲爱的爱丽丝
Dear Alice,
真希望有你的真实地址
I wish I had your real address.
我很想告诉你关于雅各的事
I wish I could tell you about Jake.
他让我感觉好了很多
He makes me feel better.
是他给了我生机
I mean, he makes me feel alive.
我胸膛上的洞
The hole in my chest,
在我和雅各相处的时候  差不多已经愈合了
well, when I’m with Jake, it's like it's almost healed
暂时地
for a while.
奎尔总嚷嚷着要过来  我觉得他有点过于喜欢你了吧
So, Quil keeps asking to come over. I think he likes you a little too much.
我真的不想卷进什么帅哥风波
Well, I’m really not into the whole cougar thing. You know？
最近怎么一提年龄你就不对劲
What's up with you and age？
我是说那个科林究竟几岁了
I mean, how old was that Cullen guy, anyway？
可是就连雅各也不能赶走我的噩梦
But even Jake can't keep the dreams away.
醒醒  贝拉
Wake up, Bella.
没事了  没事了
You're okay. You're okay.
我本以为这东西有用的  看来我猜错了
I thought this thing was starting to work, but I guess not.
我能问你点事儿吗
Can I ask you something？
和雅各布相处
Hanging out with Jacob,
的确让你稍微摆脱了那些噩梦  对吧
that seems to take your mind off things a bit, doesn't it？
你知道  有些时候
You know, sometimes
人需要学会珍惜那些对你好的人
you gotta learn to love what's good for you.
你明白我的意思吗
You know what I mean？
当然  我又知道什么呢
Of course, what do I know？
我只是个无可救药的单身汉
I’m just a terminal bachelor.
超有女人缘的男人
Famous ladies' man.
好吧
Okay.
我去睡了
I’m gonna go to bed.
我爱你
I love you.
如果我告诉你  我修不好这些车  你会说什么
lf l told you l couldn't have fixed these bikes, what would you have said？
你在怀疑自己的技术吗
Are you doubting your mad skills？
当然不是  很快就能好了
No. Definitely not. I mean, they'll run fine.
只是
It’s just,
如果聪明的话  我应该拖一拖再修好它们
maybe if I was smart, I would have dragged out the rebuild a bit.
如果你告诉我你修不好这些车的话  我应该会说  那真是太糟糕了
If you told me you couldn't fix these bikes, I would say that that's really too bad,
但咱们可以找点其他事来做
but that we're just gonna have to find something else to do.
那是山姆·尤里吗
Is that Sam Uley？
恩  他和他的小弟们
Yeah. Him and his cult.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
看见没
Did you see that？
他们不是真在打架  贝拉  他们在玩悬崖跳水
They're not really fighting, Bella. They're cliff diving.
恐怖之极  但绝对够刺激
Scary as hell, but a total rush.
- 刺激  - 我们只从低处往下跳
- A rush？- Most of us jump from lower down.
好让山姆和他手下去炫耀
We leave the showing off to Sam and his disciples.
你对他有不满吗
You have some kind of beef with him or something？
不知道
l don't know.
他们自认统治着这个地方
They just think they run this place.
恩布里把他们自己称为猛男纠察队
Embry used to call them hall monitors on steroids.
- 看他  - 那是恩布里吗
- Now look at him. - That's Embry？
- 恩  - 他怎么了
- Yeah. - What happened to him？
他经常翘课
He missed some school.
一夜之间就变成了山姆的跟屁虫
Now all of a sudden, he started following Sam around like a little puppy.
保罗和杰拉德也一样
Same thing happened with Paul and Jared.
山姆看我的眼神怪怪的
Sam keeps giving me this look,
就好象他一直在等我
like he's waiting for me or something.
快把我弄疯了
It’s kind of starting to freak me out.
那就离他远点
Well, you should just avoid him.
会的
I try.
开始吧
Okay.
- 你看上去很害怕啊  - 才没有
- You look scared. - I’m not.
好吧
All right.
- 刹车  - 握住了
- Brake？- That one.
离合器
Clutch？
很好
Good.
油门
Gas？
准备好了吗
Ready？
现在慢慢放开离合器
Now, slowly release the clutch.
贝拉
Bella.
停下
Stop.
你还好吧
You all right？
我要再试一下
I’m gonna go again.
好
Okay.
快刹车
Hit the brake！
我想再试一次
I wanna go again.
你不要命啦
Are you trying to get yourself killed？
- 我就要再试一次  - 不行
- No. l want to go again. - No. Forget it.
不许再骑摩托了
No more bikes.
天呐  你的头
Man, your head.
我的天  真对不起
Oh, my God, I’m sorry.
你在为自己流血而道歉吗
What, you're apologizing for bleeding？
恩  我想是的
Yeah. I guess I am.
只是一点血而已  没什么大不了
Well, it's just blood, Bella. No big deal.
来
There.
盯着看什么呢
What are you staring at？
你还是挺帅的
You're sort of beautiful.
你摔傻了吧
How hard did you hit your head？
不知道
I don't know.
咱们走
Let's go.
我确实在树林里看见东西了
I did see something in the woods.
当然  宝贝  我相信你
Totally. Baby, l believe you.
他不信  他只是想搏你欢心
No, he doesn't. He's just trying to get lucky.
好吧  墨黑色的  非常巨大
No, okay. It was jet black and huge.
四脚着地时比人还高
On all fours, it was still taller than a person.
一头熊吗？
A bear, maybe？
或是个外星人  没被拐走算你幸运
Or an alien. You're lucky you didn't get probed.
我确实看见了
Well, I saw it.
不是只有你看见了
You know, you're not the only one.
我爸已从警局得到报告
My dad's been getting reports at the station.
已有大概5名登山者像是被熊杀了
Like, five hikers have been killed by some bear.
但他们却找不到熊
But they can't find the bear.
看你们下次谁还敢不信我女朋友
Last time you clowns doubt my girlfriend.
这么看来
So？I mean,
贝拉又回来了
Bella's back？
我想是的
Yeah, I guess so.
好  真是  热烈欢迎
All right, that's… Well, welcome.
既然你又开口说话了
So, listen, now that you're talking
又开始吃饭了  那个  你得多吃点蛋白质才行
and eating again, which, you know, you've got to get that protein in there,
我想问下你想和我去看电影吗
I was just wondering if you wanted to go see a movie with me.
当然  我去
Yeah. Sure. Yeah, l do.
太好了
Cool.
我想想  咱可以去看
Let me see, we could check out
"反正都是爱"
Love Spelled Backwards Is Love.
标题很蠢  可是一部浪漫喜剧
You know, it's a dumb title, but it's a romantic comedy.
- 我是说  应该挺…  - 不要浪漫的
- I mean, it's supposed to be pretty… - No. No romance.
"揍脸"呢  你听过吗
How about Face Punch？Have you heard of that？
是部动作片
I mean, that's an action movie.
恩  不错
Yeah, that's perfect.
枪战  刺激
Guns, adrenaline.
是我喜欢的
That's my thing.
好吧
Okay.
我们该找些朋友一起去  你们想去看"揍脸"吗
We should get a bunch of people to go. Do you guys want to go see Face Punch？
"揍脸"啊  当然
Face Punch, yeah！
麦克  我们本来就想去看的
Mike, hey, we were supposed to watch that.
记得吗  记得预告片中
Remember, the trailer's like…
- 把脸揍得…- 记得
- "Punch faces." - I remember.
和贝拉一起的电影之夜
Yeah！Movie night with Bella.
"揍脸"？
So Face Punch, huh？
你喜欢动作片？
You like action movies？
不太喜欢
Not really.
我听说这片很烂  不怎么样
I heard it sucks. Bad.
你这么小年纪可以看这电影吗
Are you even old enough to see this movie？
我是指不用成年人陪同可以吗
I mean, you know, without, like, adult supervision.
没问题  她去给我买票
Right, yeah, well, she's buying my ticket for me.
她去买票了  好吧
She's buying it. Okay.
杰西卡放咱们鸽子  安吉拉得了肠胃炎
Jessica bailed, and Angela got the stomach flu,
埃里克去照顾她了
so Eric's taking care of her.
- 就咱们三个人了  - 很好
- It’s just us three. - Great！
- 很好  - 恩
- Great. - Yeah.
把枪放下
Put your gun down.
把枪放下  不然我爆你头
Put your gun down or I’m gonna blow your frickin' head off.
你们两个全都把枪放下
Both of you put both of your guns down
否则把你俩的头全爆了
or I’m gonna blow both of your frickin' heads off.
好吧  就这样吧  开始吧
All right, forget it, let's do this！
我觉得我要吐了
Okay, I think I’m gonna throw up.
他…
He's…
真是个窝囊废
What a marshmallow！
你应该找个胃强壮点的人出来玩
You should hold out for someone with a stronger stomach.
可以笑看血肉横飞而不呕吐的人
Someone who laughs at the gore that makes weaker men vomit.
好吧  我会留意的
Yeah. I’ll keep my eye open for that.
真替他难过  他有可能得了流感
I feel bad. He probably has that flu that's going around.
怎么了  不能牵手吗
What？I can't hold your hand？
当然能
No, of course you can.
我只是  怕你误会
I just think it means, you know, something a little different to you. So…
告诉我  你喜欢我  对吗
Okay, well, tell me something. You like me, right？
而且你觉得我还挺帅的
And you think I’m sort of beautiful？
雅各  拜托  别这样
Jacob, please, don't do this.
为什么
Why？
这样会毁了一切的
Because you're about to ruin everything.
而我需要你
And I need you.
好吧  我还有很多时间
Well, I’ve got loads of time.
我不会放弃的
I’m not gonna give up.
我也不希望你放弃
I don't want you to,
但只是因为我不希望你离开
but it's just 'cause I don't want you to go anywhere.
这真的很自私
And that's really selfish.
我不像车那样可以让你来修复
You know, I’m not like a car that you can fix up.
我再也无法走上正轨  我该对你公平一点
I’m never gonna run right. So I should be fair to you.
是因为他  对吧
It’s because of him, right？
听着
Look,
我知道他对你做过什么
I know what he did to you.
但是  贝拉  我绝对不会那样对你
But, Bella, l would never ever do that.
我永远不会伤害你  我保证
I won't ever hurt you. l promise.
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down.
相信我
You can count on me.
看来
Well,
我该回家了
I need to go home.
其实电影开始前我就觉得恶心了
I was feeling sick before the movie. Okay？
你到底哪有问题
What is your problem？
现在吗  你就是我的问题
Right now？You're my problem.
觉得恶心？ 或许你该去医院
Feeling sick？Maybe you need to go to the hospital.
你想让我把你送进医院吗
You want me to put you in the hospital？
雅各  电影都结束了  你这是干什么
Jake！Jake. Jake, the movie's over. What are you doing？
你身上好烫
You're really hot.
就象发了高烧  你没事吧
Like, you feel like you have a fever. Are you okay？
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what's happening.
我得走了
I gotta go.
这家伙真奇怪
That dude is weird.
雅各  你爸说你得了传染性腺热
Jake, your dad says you have mono.
他不让我去看你  能给我回个电话吗
He won't let me visit, but would you call me？
嘿  又是我  我只想说
Hey, it's me again. I just…
我很抱歉在电影院说了那些话
I’m sorry about what I said at the movie theater.
我只想听到你的声音  别有压力
I just wanted to hear your voice, so no pressure.
雅各布  拜托
Jacob, please…
给我回电话
Call me.
我们大概三点回来
Okay. We should be back around 3:00.
今天我可以不去钓鱼
Look, l don't have to go fishing today.
不  你去吧
Yes, you do.
是的  你得去  去吧  胡说什么呢
Yeah, you do. Go. What are you talking about？
小心点
Just be careful.
我一直都很小心
Always am.
那些熊吓不倒我  贝拉
Those bears won't get the drop on me, Bella.
我功夫很厉害的
My kung fu is strong.
雅各
Jake！
你把头发剪了
You cut your hair off？
还刺了纹身
And got a tattoo？
贝拉
Bella.
我以为你病倒了没法出来
l thought you were too sick to come outside
或者病得都没办法起床接我电话
or pick up the phone when l call.
走开
Go away.
什么
What？
走开
Go away.
你怎么了  出什么事了
What happened to you？What's…
到底出什么事了
Hey！What happened？
山姆缠上你了  是这么回事吗
Did Sam get to you？Is that what's happening？
山姆是想帮助我  不要错怪他
Sam's trying to help me. Don't blame him.
如果你非要责怪谁的话
But if you want somebody to blame,
不如去怪那些你深爱的肮脏的吸血怪物  科林一家
how about those filthy bloodsuckers you love, the Cullens？
我不知道你在说什么
l don't know what you're talking about.
你非常清楚我说的是什么
No, you know exactly what I’m talking about.
你一直在欺骗所有人  包括查理
You've been lying to everyone. Charlie.
但你骗不了我
But you can't lie to me.
- 再也不能了  贝拉  - 雅各布
- Not anymore, Bella. - Jacob！
雅各布
Jacob！
听着  贝拉
Look, Bella,
我们不能再做朋友了
we can't be friends anymore.
雅各  我知道我一直在伤害你
Look, Jake, l know that I’ve been hurting you.
这让我很痛苦  一直都很痛苦
It’s killing me. It kills me.
也许你可以给我点…
l just need… Maybe give me, like,
- 时间  - 别说了
- some time or something. - Look, don't.
不是你的问题
It’s not you.
和你无关  是我的问题
It’s not you, it's me, right？Really？
没错  是我的问题
It’s true. It is me.
我没那么好
I’m not good.
我曾经是个好孩子
l used to be a good kid.
可以后再也不是了
Not anymore.
已经无所谓了  对吗
This doesn't even matter. All right？
都结束了
This is over.
你不能和我分手
You can't break up with me.
我是说
l mean…
你是我最好的朋友
l mean, you're my best friend.
你保证过的
You promised me.
我知道
l know.
我保证过绝不伤害你  贝拉
l promised l wouldn't hurt you, Bella.
我现在就是在遵守那个诺言
And this is me keeping that promise.
回家去
Go home
别再回来了  否则你将会受到伤害
and don't come back or you're gonna get hurt.
爱丽丝
Alice,
情况…
things are…
情况又变糟了
Things are bad again.
没有雅各  我…坚持不下去
Without Jake, l just… l can't stand it.
我再没看到过爱德华
l don't see Edward anymore.
难道他真的没存在过吗
Will it really feel like he never existed？
我要找个能再看见他的地方
l will find the place where l can see him again.
贝拉
Bella.
劳伦特
Laurent.
真没想到能在这找到你
l didn't expect to find you here.
我去拜访科林一家  但他家却人去楼空
l went to visit the Cullens, but the house is empty.
没想到他们会丢下你不管
I’m surprised they left you behind.
你不是他们的…
Weren't you sort of
小宠物吗
a pet of theirs？
没错  可以这么说
Yeah. You could say that.
科林一家经常回来吗
Do the Cullens visit often？
别说真话
Lie.
当然了  经常
Yeah, absolutely, all the time.
再理直气壮点儿
Lie better.
我会告诉他们你来拜访过
I’ll tell them that you stopped by.
不过或许我不该…
But l probably shouldn't
告诉爱德华
tell Edward,
他总是戒备心很强
'cause he's pretty protective.
可他现在远在天边  不是么
But he's far away, isn't he？
你来这干什么
Why are you here？
我来帮维多利亚一个忙
I came as a favor to Victoria.
- 维多利亚？ - 她让我来看下…
- Victoria？- She asked me to see
科林一家是不是还在保护你
if you were still under the protection of the Cullens.
维多利亚认为杀了爱德华的伴侣才算扯平
Victoria feels it's only fair to kill Edward's mate,
因为他杀了她的伴侣
given he killed hers.
以牙还牙
An eye for an eye.
威胁他
Threaten him.
爱德华会知道是谁干的  他会去找你的
Edward would know who did it. And he'd come after you.
我觉得他不会
l don't think he will.
毕竟  如果他把你抛下不管
After all, how much could you mean to him
你对他又能有多重要呢
if he left you here unprotected？
我杀了你  维多利亚会不高兴的
Victoria won't be happy about my killing you,
但我却忍不住
but l can't help myself.
你让人如此的垂涎欲滴
You are so mouth-watering.
- 请别这样  你帮过我们  - 不  不  不
- Please, don't. l mean, you helped us. - No, no, no, no.
别害怕  我这样正是在帮你
Don't be afraid. I’m doing you a kindness.
维多利亚计划要慢慢折磨死你
Victoria plans on killing you slowly,
摧残你
painfully,
我会干脆些
whereas I’ll make it quick.
我保证
l promise.
你什么都不会感觉到
You will feel nothing.
爱德华  我爱你
Edward, l love you.
这不可能
l don't believe it.
- 爸爸  我看见它们了  - 看到什么了
- Dad！l saw them. - What's the matter？
- 在森林里  他们不是熊  - 什么叫"在森林里"
- In the woods. They're not bears. - What do you mean "in the woods"？
贝拉  你去森林里干什么
Bell, what the hell were you doing out in the woods？
是狼  非常巨大的狼
They're wolves. l mean, they're like huge wolves.
你确定吗  贝拉
Are you sure about that, Bella？
是的  我刚才看到了  他们在追  什么东西
Yeah！l just saw them. They were after something.
狼？
Wolves？
你看见了？
You saw them？
好吧  哈利
All right, well, Harry,
咱们去围捕它们  你能叫上些人吗
feel like going hunting？Get some of your guys together？
没问题  我只是…
Sure, yeah, I’ll just…
我知道那些狼肯定会死
By now, those wolves will be dead,
劳伦特会告诉她  没人保护我
and Laurent would have told her I’m unprotected.
维多利亚
Victoria.
我得去警局了
l should go to the station.
是  你该去
Yeah, you should. You should go.
待在家里别出去好吗
Can you just stay in the house？
贝拉
Bella！
你吓坏我了
You scared me.
- 你来干什么  - 退后  我要上来了
- What the hell are you doing？- Back up. I’m coming up.
听着  我很抱歉
Look, I’m sorry.
- 为什么道歉  - 我希望我能解释
- For what？- l wish l could explain.
可是  我不能
But l literally can't.
你有过不可告人的秘密吗
Have you ever had a secret you couldn't tell anyone,
而且那秘密还不是你的
one that wasn't yours to share？
这就是我现在的处境
Well, that's what it's like for me.
或者更糟
But worse.
你无法理解我是多么的煎熬
You have no idea how tight I’m bound.
我恨
l hate this.
我恨他们对你做的一切
l hate what they've done to you.
让我纠结的事你其实是知道的
l mean, the killer part is, you already know.
贝拉  你还记得咱们在拉布什海滩散步的事吗
Bella, do you remember when we walked on the beach at La Push？
那个
The…
那个故事
The story. The story about
关于冷血生灵的故事
the cold ones.
我想我能理解为什么你只记得那一部分
l guess l understand why that's the only part you remember.
你一定可以做些什么的
There's gotta be something that you can do.
不  这是我的命运
No. I’m in it for life.
或许咱们可以离开这里一阵子
Well, maybe we should just get out of here for a while.
就这么离开
Just leave,
只有你和我
just you and me.
你愿意吗
You'd do that？
为了你  我愿意
l would do it for you.
这不是逃避就能解决的问题  贝拉
It’s not something l can just run away from, Bella.
但如果可以的话
But l would run away with you
我愿意和你一起走
if l could.
我该走了  他们会起疑心的
l gotta go. They'll start wondering where l am.
过来
Come here.
拜托你
Please,
试着想起来
try to remember.
如果你能了解
It'd be so much easier
事情会简单很多
if you knew.
我会的  可是  雅各
I’ll try. But, Jake…
雅各  你要做什么  等等
Jake, what are you doing？Wait, Jake.
雅各
Jake.
爱德华  我很害怕
Edward, I’m scared.
你应该感到害怕
You should be.
那确实只是个古老的传说
Really, it's just like an old story.
我们不该跟别人透露这些
I’m not really supposed to say anything about it.
你知道吗  奎鲁特人经常被认为是狼人的后裔
Did you know Quileutes are supposedly descended from wolves？
贝拉
Bella？
我要见他
l need to see him.
他不在家
He's not in.
- 抱歉  我必须要见到他  - 贝拉
- Okay, I’m sorry, l really need to see him.  - Bella！
你们做了什么
What did you do？
你们究竟做了什么
Okay, what did you do？
- 你们对他做了什么  - 冷静点
- What did you do to him？ - Easy！
他不想要这样
He didn't want this.
我们做了什么  他做了什么  他跟你说了什么
What did we do？What did he do？What'd he tell you？
- 你们两个都冷静点  - 他什么都没说
- Both of you calm down.  - Nothing.
他什么都不敢说  因为他害怕你们
He tells me nothing because he's scared of you.
- 来不及了  - 贝拉  快退后
- Too late now.  - SAM: Bella, get back！
保罗  冷静下来
Paul, calm down, now！
贝拉
Bella！
快跑
Run！
雅各  快跑
Jake, run！
保罗
Paul！
把贝拉带回艾米丽那里
Hey！Take Bella back to Emily's place.
狼人的秘密被揭穿了
Guess the wolf's out of the bag.
爱丽丝  这一切都是真的吗
Alice, is it possible that everything is true？
童话和恐怖故事
The fairy tales and horror stories？
难道这世上的一切都是异常又疯狂的吗
Is it possible that there isn't anything sane or normal at all？
咱们应该回去看看雅各布怎么样了
Hey, l think we should go back and see if Jacob's okay.
保罗真该好好咬他一通  给他点教训
l hope Paul sinks some teeth in him. Serves him right.
不可能  雅各布天生勇猛
No way. Jacob's a natural.
你刚看到他腾空变身了吗  我赌五美元  保罗连他的汗毛都碰不到
You see him phase on the fly？l got five says Paul doesn't touch him.
进来吧  贝拉  我们不咬人的
Come on in, Bella. We won't bite.
我可没说不咬
Speak for yourself.
我的过错
l done me wrong
毁了一切
And done all wrong
我的过错  要自己承担
All the wrong I’ve done I’m sure I’ll live quite long
艾米丽是山姆的未婚妻  别盯着她看  山姆会难堪的
Oh, hey, about Emily, Sam's fiancée？Don't stare. It bugs Sam.
我为什么要盯着她看
Why would l stare？
你们饿了吗  这还用问吗
Are you guys hungry？Like l have to ask.
这是谁
Who's this？
贝拉·斯旺  还能有谁
Bella Swan. Who else？
原来你就是那个吸血鬼女孩
So, you're the vampire girl.
那么你是狼人女孩吧
So, you're the wolf girl.
算是吧
Guess so.
我和其中一个订婚了
Well, I’m engaged to one.
给你们的兄弟留点  女士优先  来点松饼吗
Save some for your brothers. And ladies first. Muffin？
好的  谢谢
Sure. Thanks.
让雅各去想怎么对山姆解释违约的事
Leave it to Jacob to find a way around Sam's gag order.
他什么都没告诉我
He didn't say anything to me.
这是狼人的规矩
That's a wolf thing.
不管你喜不喜欢  一定要听首领的命令
Alpha's orders get obeyed whether we want them to or not.
不信你可以试试  我们能听到同伴的想法
And check it out. We can hear each other's thoughts.
你就不能闭会儿嘴吗  这些可是机密  该死
Would you shut up？These are trade secrets. Damn it！
这妞和吸血鬼一伙的
This chick runs with vampires.
其实我没法和他们在一起的
You can't really run with vampires.
他们跑的太快了
'Cause they're fast.
真的吗  我们更快
Yeah？Well, we're faster.
现在害怕了吧
Freaked out yet？
我又不是第一次看见怪兽
You're not the first monsters I’ve met.
雅各说得对  你已经见怪不怪了
Jake's right. You're good with weird.
抱歉
Sorry.
那么  你是个狼人？
So you're a werewolf？
是  上次验证过了
Yeah. Last time l checked.
族里只有少数幸运儿拥有这种血统
A few lucky members of the tribe have the gene.
如果城里有吸血鬼  我们就会发烧
A bloodsucker moves into town and the fever sets in.
传染性腺热
Mono.
我倒希望是
Yeah. l wish.
没有办法停止这些吗
Well, can't you find a way to just stop？
这是不对的
l mean, it's wrong.
这不像选择生活方式  贝拉
It’s not a lifestyle choice, Bella.
我们生来如此  没得选择
l was born this way. l can't help it.
你真是个伪君子  你不能接受我这种怪物吗
You're such a hypocrite. What, I’m not the right kind of monster for you？
这和你是谁无关
It’s not what you are.
关键是你做了什么  他们从来不伤害别人
It’s what you do. They never hurt anybody.
而你们却杀人  雅各
You've killed people, Jake.
贝拉  我们没有杀人
Bella, we're not killing anyone.
那是谁干的
Then who is？
为了保护你们人类
What we're trying to protect you people from,
我们唯一会杀的就是
the only thing we do kill,
死血鬼
vampires.
等等  雅各  你不能
Wait, Jake, you can't.
放心  我们不会伤害你的宝贝爱人
Don't worry. We can't touch your little precious Cullens
除非他们违反约定
unless they violate the treaty.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I’m saying.
你们杀不了吸血鬼
You can't kill vampires. They'll…
他们会杀了你们的
They'll kill you.
真的吗  我们试过了  杀掉他们很容易
Really？We took out that leech with the dreads easy enough.
你是说劳伦特吗
Laurent？
他的红发女友会是下一个
And his red-headed girlfriend is next.
维多利亚在这里？
Victoria's here？
她来过  有一晚我们一直追杀她到加拿大边境
Was. We chased her all the way to the Canadian border the other night.
但她不断跑回来  我们不知道她在寻找什么
She keeps coming back. We don't know what she's after.
我知道
l do.
我
Me.
别担心  我们会守卫这里
Don't worry. We've got this place covered.
不会让她接近你和查理的
She won't get near you or Charlie.
你要小心点
Look, you've got to be careful.
她速度很快的  快得难以想象
She's fast. You don't know how fast she is.
知道吗  对我们这么没信心是一种侮辱
You know, your lack of confidence in us is a little insulting.
好了  我该走了
All right, I’d better go.
你要走了吗
You gotta go？
是啊
Yeah.
去杀吸血鬼
Got a vampire to kill.
爱丽丝  我很好
Alice, I’m all right.
除了孤身一人的时候
Until I’m alone.
而最近尤其如此
And lately, that's all the time.
雅各布走了  去追杀维多利亚了
Jacob's gone. He's hunting Victoria.
而查理在追查雅各布
And Charlie's hunting Jacob.
你又不在这里
And you're gone.
爱德华也走了
And so is Edward.
我现在一无所有
And there's just nothing now.
哈利  你发现什么了吗
You got something, Harry？
没  什么都没有
Nope. Nothing.
但我知道要到去往何处
But l realize where l have to go,
知道怎样做才能再见到他
what l have to do to see him again.
脑海中的眼泪
A tear in my brain
让声音蜂拥而入
Allows the voices in
他们要把你推下轨道
They wanna push you off the path
用那频率的脉冲
With their frequency wires
你没有错
And you can do no wrong
在我眼中
In my eyes
你没有错
You can do no wrong
在我眼中
In my eyes
醉酒的推销员
A drunken salesman
你听力损伤
Your hearing damage
你心事重重
Your mind is restless
他们说你会痊愈
They say you're getting better
可你却越陷越深
But you don't feel any better
话筒在爆炸
Your speakers are blowing
震耳欲聋
Your ears are wrecking
你听力损伤
Your hearing damage
但愿一切会好起来
You wish you felt better
你没有错
You can do no wrong
在我眼中
In my eyes
不要这样
Don't do this.
你想让我做人类
You wanted me to be human.
看看我
Watch me.
求你
Please.
为了我
For me.
只有这样你才能和我在一起
You won't stay with me any other way.
贝拉  不要这样
Bella, please.
余音不绝
This constant noise all the time
你是我眼中的全部
Even though you're the only one l see
呼吸
Breathe！
快点呼吸
贝拉  醒过来  呼吸
Come on, Bella, breathe！
贝拉  能听到我说话吗
Bella？Bella, can you hear me？
雅各
Jake？
起来
Come here.
你到底想干什么
What the hell were you thinking？
我只是想看一些东西
l just wanted to see something.
送她回家  我要去去哈利家帮忙
Get her home！I’m gonna go help out over at Harry's place.
哈利家怎么了
What happened at Harry's？
哈利心脏病突发
Harry Clearwater had a heart attack.
查理和我爸爸都到他家去了
Charlie and my dad are over at his place with his family.
他还好吗
Is he okay？
他去世了
He's gone.
来  我帮你把身上弄干然后送你回家
Come on. I’ll get you something dry and drive you home.
我身上暖得很
108 degrees over here.
天啊
God！
我的手都快冻僵了
My hands are freezing.
从来都不怕冷的感觉一定很好
It must be nice, never getting cold.
狼人都是这样
It’s a wolf thing.
不是
It’s not.
只有雅各布很温暖
It's a Jacob thing.
你真的很温暖
You're just warm.
就像是  自己的太阳
You're like your own sun.
太好了  现在你已经了解我了
This is better, now that you know about me.
但是…
But…
你看到艾米丽的样子了
You saw what happened to Emily.
山姆当时很生气
Sam got angry.
仅仅因为一秒钟的情绪失控
Lost it for a split second.
而艾米站得离他太近了
Em was standing too close.
造成永远无法弥补的错误
He'll never be able to take that back.
万一我突然对你生气怎么办
What if l got mad at you？
有些时候
Sometimes,
我感觉自己快要消失了
l feel like I’m gonna disappear.
不是因为你想听我才说
Okay, not that you need me
我永远都会这么说
to tell you something like this,
你不会失去自我
but l always will. You're not gonna lose yourself.
我不会让那发生
l wouldn't let that happen.
怎么做
How？
我会一直对你说
I’ll tell you all the time
你有多特别
how special you are.
谢谢你  为我做的一切
Thank you. For everything.
等等
Wait.
这儿有个吸血鬼
There's a vampire.
你怎么知道的
How do you know？
我能闻出来  我要带你离开
l can smell it. I’m getting you out of here.
那是卡莱尔的车
That's Carlisle's car.
他们在这里
They're here.
贝拉  这是个陷阱  别去
Bella, it's a trick！Stop！You gotta come with me！
他们不会伤害我的
They won't hurt me.
如果科林回来的话  那这里就是他们的辖区
lf a Cullen is back here, this is their territory.
按照合约我们只能保卫自己的领地
Treaty says we can only defend on our own lands.
- 在这里我没法保护你  - 好  没事的  你没必要保护我
- l can't protect you here. - Okay. That's okay. You don't have to.
你越界了
You're about to cross a line.
那就别分界线
Then don't draw one.
求你了
Please？
爱丽丝
Alice？
- 天啊  你怎么…  - 贝拉
- Oh, my God！What are you…  - Bella！
对不起  我只是无法相信你会在这儿
I’m sorry, l just, l can't believe you're here. Is…
可以给我解释一下你为什么还活着吗
Would you like to explain to me how you're alive？
什么？
What？
我看见你跳崖了
l saw a vision of you. You jumped off a cliff.
你为什么要自杀
Why in the hell would you try and kill yourself？
查理怎么办
l mean, what about Charlie？
- 还有…  - 我没有想自杀
- What about…  - l didn't try to kill myself.
我是悬崖跳水
I was cliff jumping.
消遣而已
Recreationally.
很有趣的
It was fun.
我从来没见过这么玩命的傻瓜
l have never met anyone more prone to life-threatening idiocy.
他…
Does…
你告诉他了吗
Did you tell him？
没有
No.
他只是每隔几个月来一个电话
He only calls in once every few months.
他说他想一个人待着
He said he wants to be alone.
贝拉  为什么会有这么大的狗臭味
Bella, what is that God-awful wet dog smell？
因为我吧
That's probably me.
或是雅各布
Or it's Jacob.
谁是雅各布
Jacob who？
雅各布是狼人
Jacob's kind of a werewolf.
贝拉  不要和狼人交朋友
Bella！Werewolves are not good company to keep.
不用你替她做主
Speak for yourself.
我必须来看看你是否安全
l had to see you were safe.
我记得你说在这没法保护我
l thought you couldn't protect me here.
好吧  我不在乎了
Guess l don't care.
我不会伤害她的
Well, I’m not gonna hurt her.
是的  你只是一个无害的吸血鬼
No, you're just a harmless Cullen.
我说的是另外一个  因为你们她想杀了贝拉
I’m talking about the other bloodsucker who tried to kill Bella because of you.
维多利亚
Victoria？
维多利亚一直在附近
Yeah, Victoria's been around.
我没看见过她
l didn't see her.
我也没看见有人从水里把你救出来
l didn't see you get pulled out of the water, either.
我看不见你和你那群狗杂种
l can't see past you and your pack of mutts.
你最好别惹我
Don't get me upset…
- 不然大家都不好看  - 别闹了  停  停  停
- …or things are gonna get very ugly.  - Hey, stop. Stop, stop, stop, stop.
你们先聊
I’ll give you a minute.
你不会走的  你还会回来的
You're not going anywhere. You're gonna come back,
- 对吧  - 只要你把狗赶走
- right？ - As soon as you put the dog out.
他来了吗
Is he…
还有其他人吗  科林一家回来了几个
Are there others？ How many Cullens are here
要待多久
and how long are they staying？
没有
No.
只有爱丽丝
It’s just Alice.
她愿意待多久就待多久
And she can stay as long as she'd like.
其他人还回来吗
Well, are the rest coming back？
不
No.
据我所知  不回来
Not that l know of.
还有别的事吗
Anything else？
没了
That's it.
如果没事你最好赶快回山姆那里
Well, if that's all, then you'd better go run back to Sam.
我又这样了
I’ve done it again.
总是违背承诺
l keep breaking my promise.
咱们两个没必要这样的
We don't have to do this to each other.
咱们有必要这样
Yes, we do.
贝拉
Bella…
这里是斯旺家
Swan residence.
他不在
He's not here right now.
他去安排葬礼了
He's arranging a funeral.
谁的电话
Who was that？
怎么了
What？
总来碍事
Always in the way.
到底是谁
Who was that？
贝拉  你别管
Bella, step back.
- 雅各布  是谁  - 贝拉  刚才是爱德华
- Jake, who was that？ - Bella！Bella, it's Edward.
他以为你死了  罗莎莉告诉了他我来这里了
He thinks you're dead. Rosalie told him why l came here.
你为什么要…你为什么不让我跟他说话
Why would you…Why didn't you let me speak to him？
- 他没有找你  - 贝拉
- He didn't ask for you.  - Bella.
- 我不管  - 贝拉  贝拉  他要去找沃尔图里家族了
- l don't care！ - Bella. Bella！He's going to the Volturi.
他也想去死
He wants to die, too.
是他抛弃你的  他离开了你  记得吗
He left you, Bella.  He didn't want you anymore. Remember？
但我不能让他心怀内疚的去自杀
No, I’m not gonna let him kill himself out of guilt.
那你爸爸怎么办
What about your dad？
我已经18岁了  法律上讲我来去自由  我还留了字条
I’m 18. I’m legally free to go, and l left a note.
求你了  贝拉
Please, Bella,
别走好吗
just stay here.
为了查理
For Charlie.
或是为了我
Or for me.
我必须得去
l have to go.
求你了
I’m begging you.
别走
Please.
再见  雅各布
Goodbye, Jacob.
好吧
Okay.
你心意已决吗
So you've made up your minds.
你的天赋如此珍贵
I’m afraid your particular gifts
不应该被毁掉
are too valuable to destroy.
如果对命运不甘心  可以加入我们
But if you're unhappy with your lot, join us.
你能为我们效力  我们会非常高兴的
We would be delighted to utilize your skills.
你不想留下来和我们待在一起吗
Won't you consider staying with us？
你知道最终的结果是什么
You know it will happen anyway.
有因就有果
Not without cause.
真可惜
Such a waste.
这辆车不是你租来的吧
I’m guessing you didn't rent this car？
我猜你应该不会反对偷车吧
l figured you wouldn't be opposed to grand theft auto.
今天不
Not today.
怎么了  你看见什么了
What？What do you see？
他们拒绝了他
They refused him.
- 那会怎样  - 他准备现身
- So？ - He's gonna make a scene.
- 在众人面前暴露自己的身份  - 不  什么时候
- Show himself to the humans.  - No！When？
他会一直等到中午  太阳最高的时候
He's gonna wait until noon, when the sun's at its highest.
爱丽丝  你最好快点
God, Alice, you got to hurry up.
那就是我特拉城
There's Volterra.
- 他们为什么都穿红色的衣服  - 圣马可斯节
- Why are they all in red？ - San Marco's Day festival.
为了庆祝吸血鬼被驱逐出这个城市
They're commemorating the expulsion of vampires from the city.
这情况对咱们有利
It’s the perfect setting.
沃尔图里家族不会让他露出真实面貌的
The Volturi will never let him get far enough to reveal himself.
只有5分钟了
We have five minutes.
贝拉  放松点  深呼吸
l know, Bella, just breathe.
爱丽丝
Alice！
你是唯一一个他预见不到的人
Bella, you're the only one he can't see coming.
如果我去了  他会知道我的想法  会觉得我欺骗他而迫不及待去死
lf l go, he'll read my thoughts. He'll think I’m lying. He'll rush into it.
- 我该去哪  - 他就在钟塔下面
- Where do l go？ - He'll be under the clock tower. Go！
不要
Don't！
这是天堂吗
Heaven.
赶快进去
You have to move.
睁开眼睛  看看我  我还活着
Open your eyes. Look at me. I’m alive.
你必须赶快进去
You have to move.
贝拉
Bella.
- 是你  - 是我
- You're here.  - I’m here.
你还活着
You're alive.
没错
Yes.
我想让你再一次看到我
l needed to make you see me once.
必须得让你知道我还活着
You had to know that l was alive,
你不必为任何事感到愧疚
that you didn't have to feel guilty about anything.
现在我可以让你走了
l can let you go now.
我做的一切都不是出于愧疚
l never acted out of guilt.
只是  没有你  我活不下去
l just couldn't live in a world where you don't exist.
- 但你说过…- 我撒谎了
- But you said…  - l lied.
我只能撒谎  而你如此轻易地相信了我
l had to lie. But you believed me so easily.
因为你不可能爱我
Because it doesn't make sense for you to love me.
我什么都不是  只是平凡的人类
l mean, I’m nothing. I’m human. I’m nothing.
贝拉  你就是我的一切
Bella, you're everything to me.
一切
You're everything.
我不需要你们的帮忙了  先生们
l won't be needing your services after all, gentlemen.
埃罗想要再和你谈谈
Aro wants to speak with you again.
我没破坏任何法则
No rules were broken.
尽管如此  不过咱们最好还是换个地方谈
Nonetheless, we should take this conversation to a more appropriate venue.
好
Fine.
贝拉  你去和大家一起欢度节日吧
Bella, why don't you go and enjoy the rest of the festival？
这女孩得和咱们一起走
The girl comes with us.
不行  想都别想
No. You can go to hell.
别这样  伙计们
Come on, guys.
这是个节日嘛  不想引人围观吧
It’s a festival. You wouldn't want to make a scene.
不想
We wouldn't.
够了
Enough.
珍
Jane.
埃罗派我来看一下为什么这么久
Aro sent me to see what was taking so long.
按她说的做
Just do as she says.
你们先请
Go ahead.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
你呢
Are you？
不
No.
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 她是人类吗  - 是的
- Is she human？ - Yes.
她知道这一切吗
Does she know？
知道
Yes.
那她为什么
Then, why would…
想要成为
She wants to be.
她会变成吸血鬼的
And so she will be.
或是甜点
Or dessert.
妹妹  让你去找一个你却带回来两个
Sister. They send you out to get one and you bring back two.
还有半个
And a half.
太聪明了
Such a clever girl.
多么令人惊喜啊
What a happy surprise！
贝拉竟然还活着
Bella is alive after all.
实在是太美妙了  不是吗
Isn't that wonderful？
我就喜欢大团圆结局
l love a happy ending.
太稀有了
They are so rare.
你的小歌手
La Tua Cantante(Your Singer)
你的血液太诱人了
Her blood appeals to you so much
让我充满渴望
it makes me thirsty.
你怎么做到的能离她这么近
How can you stand to be so close to her？
- 不是那么容易  - 我能理解
- It’s not without difficulty.  - Yes, l can see that.
埃罗通过触摸就可以读出我的所有想法
Aro can read every thought I’ve ever had with one touch.
现在所有的事你都知道了
And now you know everything.
那就继续吧
So get on with it.
你自己也是个不错的读心者  爱德华
You are quite a soul reader yourself, Edward.
虽然你无法知道贝拉在想什么
Though you can't read Bella's thoughts.
太神奇了
Fascinating.
我想看看  你是否也能屏蔽我的能力
l would love to see if you are an exception to my gifts, as well.
我是否有这样的荣幸呢
Would you do me the honor？
有趣
Interesting.
我什么都读不到
l see nothing.
我在想
l wonder if…
她是否对所有的能力都免疫呢
Let us see if she's immune to all our powers.
可以试试吗  珍
Shall we, Jane？
- 不要  - 痛苦
- No！ - Pain.
停下
Stop！
求你停下来
Stop！Please！Stop！
求你了  别再伤害他
Stop！Just stop hurting him！Please！Please！
珍
Jane？
主人
Master？
继续吧  亲爱的
Go ahead, my dear.
这可能会有些疼
This may hurt just a little.
太不寻常了
Remarkable！
她击败了咱们所有人
She confounds us all.
那么我们该如何处置你呢
So what do we do with you now？
你知道你该怎么做的  埃罗
You already know what you're going to do, Aro.
她知道的太多了
She knows too much.
她是个麻烦
She's a liability.
说的没错
That's true.
菲利克斯
Felix？
不
No！
别这样  求你  不要这样
Please！No！No！Please, please！
杀了我吧  饶了他
Kill me！Kill me！Not him.
多么伟大啊
How extraordinary.
你居然愿意为我们这种人放弃生命
You would give up your life for someone like us.
为一个吸血鬼
A vampire.
一个没有灵魂的恶魔
A soulless monster.
离她远点
Just get away from her！
你根本不了解他的灵魂
You don't know a thing about his soul.
你们两个之中肯定要死一个
Maybe it's one or the other.
真是太悲哀了
This is a sadness.
除非你主动赐予她长生不老
lf only it were your intention to give her immortality.
等等
Wait！
贝拉将会成为咱们的一员
Bella will be one of us.
我预见到了
I’ve seen it.
我会亲自将她变成吸血鬼的
I’ll change her myself.
太美妙了
Mesmerizing.
能预见未发生之事
To see what you have seen before it has happened.
你的能力将会让你成为一个迷人的
Your gifts will make for an intriguing
不死之身
immortal,
伊莎贝拉
Isabella.
去吧
Go now.
去做准备吧
Make your preparations.
我们来把事情完成
Let us be done with this.
海迪随时都会去拜访你们的
Heidi will arrive any moment.
感谢你们的来访
Thank you for your visit.
我们也会回访的
We will return the favor.
我建议你们及早实现诺言
l would advise that you follow through on your promise soon.
我们不会给第二次机会的
We do not offer second chances.
再见了  我年轻的朋友们
Goodbye, my young friends.
收获不小嘛  海迪
Nice fishing, Heidi.
看起来相当美味多汁呢
Yes, they do look rather juicy.
给我留点
Save some for me.
请走这边  不要走散
This way, please. Stay together.
不  不
Stop！Stop！
你还在这
You're here.
放心睡吧
You can sleep.
你什么时候醒来我都会守在你身边
I’ll still be here when you wake up.
贝拉  我当初离开的唯一原因
Bella, the only reason l left
只是想要保护你
was because l thought l was protecting you.
我希望你可以
l needed you
像普通人一样快乐的生活
to have a chance at a normal, happy life.
你如此轻易就离开我
It was so easy for you to leave.
离开你是我100年来做过的最痛苦的事
Leaving you was the hardest thing I’ve done in 100 years.
我发誓
And l swear,
永远不会再让你失望
l will never fail you again.
真的抱歉
I’m so sorry.
- 查理来了  - 嘿
- Charlie's coming.  - Hey.
你还好吧
You okay？
挺好
I’m fine.
爸  你不用担心我
Dad, you don't have to worry.
上次你也是这样说  然后就失踪了
You know, last time you said that, you took off.
整整三天
l didn't see you for three days.
我知道错了  爸爸
I’m really sorry, Dad.
贝拉  再也不许这样了
Bella, do not ever do that to me again.
永远都不许
Ever.
你被禁足了
And you're grounded
直到死为止
for the rest of your life.
好吧
Okay.
严格说来我没有违反他的规定
I’m not technically breaking any of his rules.
他说过  我不能踏进门口一步
He did say l couldn't take a step inside the door.
我是从窗子进来的
l came in through the window.
他不会轻易原谅我的
He's not gonna forgive me easily.
我知道
l know.
你可以吗
Can you？
请原谅我吧
l hope you can,
没了你我真不知道该怎么活下去
'cause l honestly don't know how to live without you.
过来
Come here.
一旦爱丽丝把我改变了
Once Alice changes me,
你就再也别想抛下我
you can't get rid of me.
她不一定要转变你
She won't need to change you.
还有其他方法可以保住沃尔图里的秘密
There are always ways to keep the Volturi in the dark.
不  不
No. No.
你们都知道我想要什么
You all know what l want.
我也知道我的要求很过分
And l know how much I’m asking for.
我认为唯一公平的方法就是大家投票表决
The only thing that l can think of for it to be fair is to just vote.
- 你在瞎说什么  - 闭嘴
- You don't know what you're talking about.  - Shut up.
爱丽丝
Alice？
我已经当你是姐妹了
l already consider you my sister.
- 我同意  - 谢谢
- Yes.  - Thank you.
我也同意
l vote "yes."
不用一直想要杀你应该会很不错
It would be nice to not want to kill you all the time.
对不起
I’m sorry.
对于以前的所作所为我感到非常抱歉
I’m really sorry to both of you for how I've acted,
同时  我也非常感激你勇敢地
and I’m really grateful that you were brave enough
救出了我的弟弟
to go and save my brother.
但这不是我会选择的生活
But this isn't a life l would have chosen for myself.
如果是我  我希望有人会阻止我
And l wish that there'd been someone to vote "no" for me.
所以  我反对
So, no.
我当然同意了
I vote "Hell, yeah".
咱们可以一起和沃尔图里干一架
And we can pick a fight with these Volturi some other way.
我早就当你是一家人了
I already consider you a part of the family.
同意
Yes.
你为什么要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me？
你知道这意味着什么
You know what this means.
没有她你就不活了  这让我别无选择
You've chosen not to live without her, which leaves me no choice.
我不想失去我的儿子
I won't lose my son.
我想等到毕业以后  这样查理会比较容易接受
I’ll wait until after graduation to make it easier on Charlie.
爱德华  我希望由你亲自完成
Edward, I want you to be the one to do it.
他想和我谈谈
He wants to talk to me.
你现在还活着
So you're still alive for now.
他认为  是我把你带走了
He thinks it's me keeping you away.
你他妈别偷听我的想法
You stay the hell out of my head.
雅各布  我知道你有话对我说
Jacob, I know you have something to say to me.
你不介意让我先说点什么吧
But l want to say something to you first, if that's all right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你在我不在的时候保护她
Thank you for keeping Bella alive when I didn't.
你不用客气
No. You didn't.
我保护她不是因为你
And it wasn't for your benefit, trust me.
我还是很感激你
I’m still grateful.
但是现在我回来了
But I’m here now.
除非她赶我走  否则我不会离开她半步
I’m not gonna leave her side until she orders me away.
走着瞧
We'll see.
该轮到我说了
Hey, my turn to talk.
我来是想提醒你别忘了协议里的重点
I’m here to remind you about a key point in the treaty.
我没忘
I haven't forgotten.
什么重点
What key point？
如果他们咬了人类
lf any of them bites a human,
停战协议就会结束
the truce is over.
但我是自愿的就与你无关了
But if I choose it, it has nothing to do with you.
我不会让你…
No. No, I won't let you.
你不能变成和他们一样  贝拉
You're not gonna be one of them, Bella.
这你管不着
It’s not up to you.
你知道我们会怎样对你  我别无选择
You know what we'll do to you. I won't have a choice.
贝拉  咱们走吧
Bella, please, come.
等等
Wait.
他会伤害我吗  读下他的想法
Is he gonna hurt me？Read his mind.
雅各
Jake,
我爱你
I love you.
所以  求求你
So, please,
不要逼我做抉择
don't make me choose,
因为我一定会选择他
'cause it'll be him.
我永远都会选他
It’s always been him.
贝拉
Bella…
- 再见  雅各布  - 不用你替她做主
- Goodbye, Jacob.  - No, you don't speak for her！
贝拉  咱们走
Bella, get out of here.
住手
Stop！
你们之中任何一人受伤  我都会难过
You can't hurt each other without hurting me.
雅各
Jake.
他是对的
He's right.
你不该变成我这个样子
You shouldn't become what l am.
你做不到吗
I can't do this alone.
求你等一等
Then, please, just wait.
给我五年的时间
Just give me five years.
这太久了
That's too long.
那么三年
Then three？
你真是固执
You're so stubborn.
你到底要等什么
What are you waiting for？
如果你要我亲自去做的话
l have one condition
我只有一个条件
if you want me to do it myself.
什么条件
What's the condition？
我们要永远在一起
And then forever.
这正是我想要的
That's what I’m asking.
嫁给我吧  贝拉
Marry me, Bella.